I'm here.
I almost forgot the timer I put.
But I made it.
What's going on?
I know I'm a little bit late here.
How's it going everybody?
Are you having a good day?
Today is, what day is it today?
It's Wednesday, isn't it?
Yeah.
Wait, the Dutch oven?
Isn't that like a pan?
Or not a pan, but like... for the stove, right?
It's either that or some kind of sexual act.
It's one of the two.
Because I feel like there's also a sexual act called something like that.
Oh yeah, Isaac will be bound up tight today.
It's true, I'm not kidding.
I forgot the exact word of it, but it's a thing.
And it's not nice.
Am
I a doubter or a believer?
I'm always a believer.
If you're talking about believing in myself, then yes, always a believer.
A Dutch oven is farting under the sheets?
Ah, that's what that was, yes.
So it wasn't sexual, but it was something to do with, you know, the butt.
That's what that was, yes.
True.
Have you seen the Carol Moon Crater clip?
No, I haven't.
If you're talking about Artemis stuff, then I've seen most of it.
Maybe I just don't understand the naming scheme you're using there.
I'm trying to keep up on all the Artemis stuff, it's really interesting.
I've always been curious, do you read the on-screen chat or some other chat?
No.
Not while playing.
But I have the OBS window up, right?
Where there's a tiny chat window.
So if there's technical issues and you guys spam and I happen to look over, then I'll see it.
Otherwise I would be totally paranoid, you know, like if there's a technical issue I wouldn't have any idea.
What are these notes on-screen?
It's Edmond Macmillan, I think his name is.
The guy who made this game.
These were the preliminary notes he took apparently when he was coming up with the game design.
Like very early stages.
It's part of the art book or something, I found it online.
I thought it looked cool.
Are you doing a sasal warmup?
I don't know actually, maybe I won't.
Maybe we'll do a challenge warmup.
Actually, how about a good old Isaac warmup?
We haven't touched Isaac in a while.
I like that.
No, I mean, right?
Okay, hold on.
What do you mean, Reef?
Do you see chat with the font on screen?
No, so right now I have the actual Twitch dashboard up.
So I can read you guys' chat.
It's a little more up to date for me.
And it's also nicer to look at, I guess.
I'd like to see some more greed mode.
You know what?
Let's do it then.
We're gonna do some greed mode as well today.
You know what?
Actually, let's take a little bit of input here.
So I'm gonna throw in my vote for Isaac.
We're gonna do at least one Isaac run.
What else do you guys want to see today?
I'm gonna do a little bit of everything, I think.
So let me know.
Because I'm actually not sure what I want to do.
Some challenges?
You got it.
We're gonna do some challenges as well.
Get to work!
Okay, okay, okay.
Give me a moment here.
Eulith?
I like it.
Yeah, actually, Eulith.
We can do Eulith a little bit.
Eulith and greed, you got it.
Ukraine?
We'll see if we have time for everything though.
Magdalene or Samson?
I think I already played those characters though, but I do not quite remember how they work.
Play whatever is most difficult?
Well, that would be Judas for me.
I think Judas is super difficult, but it could be one of those characters where if you get over the initial hump of having only one heart, you know, then it'll take off from there.
But yeah, as a new player Judas is definitely very tough for me.
Be aware, if you do it daily, they have everything in the game unlocked.
Okay, I'm not gonna do the daily then.
That's just gonna confuse me.
Daily run sounds like something that could be really cool later on when I have everything unlocked.
Okay, guys, I got some good input.
I will transition to a gaming mode.
Because I actually just want to get going.
I've got coffee and water today.
I even bought a step counter.
I'm that much of a fitness freak now.
Not that I would call it fitness, maybe more like a lifestyle freak.
I'm getting all the way into it, guys.
Trying to get in 10,000 steps a day and shit.
You got to get in at least 10,000 steps a day and at least a couple Isaac wins a day, you know, that's part of the routine.
All right.
Let's see here.
That's beautiful.
Oh, yeah.
Cheers.
Okay.
Let's go.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, hold on.
We still haven't found any more parts of this picture.
That's what I'm gonna do today as well.
We're gonna start things off with an Isaac run just to get into it.
And then I think we're gonna just keep rolling.
I'm gonna play really well today.
All these other days, I've actually just been pretending to be bad, you know.
But nowadays, or today, I will actually make myself good.
You'll see what I mean.
Hold on, I got to move my mouse pad out of the way.
One of the rare games where I don't... where the mouse pad actually makes things worse.
There we go.
All right.
Let me just see.
Okay, okay.
So anything special with Isaac?
That was just the most standard, right?
Three hearts, no items, one bomb.
Good stuff, man.
All right, let's see.
3.5 damage.
We have some poops to start off.
Love to see it.
Actually, Isaac is very good all around here.
Okay, there we go.
Having trouble aiming a little bit here.
And another bomb.
Let's look for tinted... we're not gonna miss a single tinted rock today.
There's nothing here.
Oh, no keys though.
But if I put a bomb here, I think I can open both.
I'm so good.
That's beautiful.
And we get a key as well.
Oh, what a start.
You know what?
I shouldn't have used the key there in case I found or will find a treasure room.
That was a bit of a misplay there.
But it's okay.
Surely we'll find another key.
There's a key.
And a car battery.
Not really interested in that.
Also, Isaac starts with zero luck.
We have some healing here for later if we need it.
Very convenient start here.
It's lust.
I forgot what you do.
You just follow me?
Oh, wait, is that?
I see how it works.
He's lusting for me.
He wants to get up close and personal.
That just... Oh, he drops an item?
Wow, the virus.
More speed.
Poison's enemy on contact.
We don't like contact though.
Wait, Poison's enemy's on contact?
Is that supposed to be like an STD reference or something?
I feel like that's what that is.
I mean, he's called lust.
Is that why he dropped that?
I'm in trouble here.
No, I'm not.
Okay, get these guys out of here.
So many poops.
Okay.
Oh, oh my God.
Wow.
Just like that, huh?
Guys, this couldn't be a better start.
If I don't win this run, then I will never forgive myself.
Like, it doesn't get better than this.
This is the best start of all time.
Okay, let's play this really well.
Boink.
That's so beautiful.
Look at that precision.
Insanity.
Okay, destroy that.
Judgment.
Oh, wait a minute, what's happening?
What's happening over here?
Hold on a minute.
Cursor on screen.
Oh, shit, sorry.
Sorry about that.
Why is the cursor on the screen?
Hold on.
Maybe I can actually hide that in a better way.
I can do... uncheck capture cursors.
That never happens again.
Okay.
I mean, when I looked over and I just saw this wall, I was like, wait a minute, what the fuck is going on?
Am I muted or something?
I feel like that's not a big issue.
It's like, isn't the cursor like a tiny fucking thing?
So we got two of the worlds.
No, we got judgment and the world.
Judgment is the one that spawns the little guy.
Ah, he wants hearts.
The question is, though, he wants a half a red heart.
Okay, good, he doesn't take my blue.
That's it.
I'm going to go back and grab the healing.
Look at that, beautifully calculated as well, the exact amount of healing I needed.
And I got nothing out of it.
Feels bad, man.
I think I will use this here.
Secret room discovered.
Bob's curse.
More bombs, bomb damage, poisons enemies, and bomb explosions leave behind poison gas.
Okay, I think it's immune to poison effects.
That's very good.
Not bad at all.
Blow that up.
Oh, rich.
Oh, my goodness.
Do I spent my last key, though, on this?
Yes, I do.
Of course.
Of course, I do.
Nice.
Now we can go back to the beggar and give him some more health.
Short fuse.
Bombs detonate faster, but they deal more damage.
I don't like that one at all.
Because I feel like there's a higher chance I will mess up myself, you know, instead of the enemy.
Well, that's not good.
I'll be back.
Is it up here?
Yeah.
Give me something!
These things are useless!
I thought at least since I'm giving them my HP, I would get something really good in return.
Turns out that's not the case.
Um, I could also walk in here.
Nah.
Maybe not worth it.
Ah, it's definitely worth it, though, right?
Want blue heart for this?
Okay, so far not worth it.
It is a gamble.
Oh, my God.
I should have listened to my gut instinct.
It's okay.
The first boss is easy.
I'm gonna blow this guy up.
What the hell?
Okay, these guys shoot diagonally.
How many flies?
Nice.
Okay, look for tinted rocks.
I don't see any.
It's time for the boss.
Monstro!
No problem.
Come on, jump to me.
Honestly, I feel like the bosses are not that hard, you know?
The rooms are definitely some of the harder things in the game.
Okay, then again, these are one of the easier bosses, but still.
Like, when you learn the patterns, right?
Like, for example, the foreskin guy, ideally, you would never take damage against him.
Because he is very predictable.
You just gotta stay on top of things.
In fact, we're gonna do a no-hit run now, from now on.
It's synth oil.
More damage in range.
Don't mind if I do.
And you know what's nice about playing Isaac?
Is that I'm not gonna feel down when I don't get extra HP upgrades.
You know?
Because I already have the HP.
It's so nice.
Do I go back, though?
I don't.
I keep going.
I mean, I keep going.
Let's do it.
Basement 2.
I'm kidding about the no-hit run, by the way.
It's impossible for me.
I mean, I'm gonna try, but... you know.
I could... I mean, I'm rich.
I should do this, I think.
Why does everyone want my blood, dammit?
Maybe I'll give this guy my blood.
But I need to find hearts first, and then I'll come back.
If not, I'm gonna end up bombing everything.
Nice.
Would love to find a shop.
Because I'm rich.
Also, if you're really gonna optimize, I wouldn't destroy this poop.
Because there are certain items that increase my chances of finding stuff in the poop.
Oh!
So I'm actually gonna wait.
Thanks.
That was my last key.
Leech.
Familiar that chases and damages enemies.
Heals Isaac for half red heart.
When it's damaged, kills Ne... Wow!
Okay, that's better than I thought.
I mean, I've had this guy before, but apparently I didn't realize the potential.
Because this is crazy.
Can we please...
get to it?
Oh, that was a bomb guy!
Why is he not attacking anyone, though?
Come on, man.
Nice.
Oh!
You're gonna spawn some spiders or something, flies?
No, a bomb, okay.
Too bad that didn't reveal a secret room, huh?
I do actually have a bunch of bombs.
I could go fishing for the secret rooms.
Oh, god.
Oh, this guy explodes, okay.
Nice.
We got a shot, baby!
Oh, no key, though!
Okay, we gotta find a key.
Hope we find the item again that goes gym, gym, gym, gym.
That was so much fun.
I can't really get to the other buttons, unfortunately.
We got a fiery guy.
Whoa!
Oh, I got healed!
Amazing.
So, ideally, when I'm low HP, I should let my familiar finish off enemies.
That sounds really freaking good, actually.
If it actually works as well as I think it will, then we are rolling.
I'm gonna wait with these poops.
Just a bit.
Who knows what we'll find?
Beautiful.
Look for tinted.
Nothing is tinted here.
Man, so far, it's really smooth.
I gotta find a key, though.
Let's go to the arcade.
I think it's time that we destroy all the poops.
Wow.
Man.
I wonder how much of this has to do with my luck.
I'm at zero, but with all the other characters, I seem to be in the negative quite a bit of time.
So, I don't know if that has an effect on that.
There is a bit of healing scattered around.
So, I could actually give you...
These guys suck ass.
Time to die.
Okay, no keys for me, unfortunately.
I could try to donate.
No, I only have one full heart left to heal with.
I think I'm gonna go get that.
Man, I'm so sad I can't get to the shop.
I have so much money.
Oh, shit, there's a rock there.
How sad is this, huh?
It's boss time.
Larry.
Larry shall die.
I'm gonna put a bomb down.
That hit nothing.
Incredible.
Oh, it got poisoned by it, though.
Hey!
Oh, the poison is actually pretty good.
Holy shit.
Man, it's a stat increase based on whichever one is the lowest.
Okay, hold on a minute.
You wanna see some five-head play here?
I could wait with this.
Go in here first.
Potentially get, like, a stat upgrade.
How about wait?
Nah, I mean, you understand what I mean, right?
But that's, like, too advanced.
I can't even think about that.
What do we got?
Monster manual and rotten baby.
Following familiar that generates blue flies?
Oh, man, it doesn't poison?
That's too bad, because I'm immune to poison.
I thought it would at least poison, given the fact that it's rotten and green.
Honestly, I don't know if I want any of these.
It's probably the baby, if anything.
Generates blue flies.
Something else I have to think about actively is these combos.
So see this one?
Spun 2 out of 3.
I should be prioritizing items that give me the last point in that.
So I end up with 3 out of 3.
You know?
This is Bob?
Apparently that's 1 out of 3?
Because this is something I don't really pay too much attention to.
And this is conjoined.
This one is bookworm.
Okay.
Um...
Why not?
We gained demon and lost angel.
Alright.
I'm leaving.
That's all the HP you're gonna get from me.
Oh, we found a key!
That's huge!
Time to go to the shop, baby!
Hell yeah!
That's mega huge.
Also, I think I forgot some poops.
Somewhere.
On the east side.
Lower east side.
What do we got here?
The jar!
Spawn red heart pickups stored in the jar.
Collect red hearts while at full health to store them.
This isn't active.
You know what?
I think I'm gonna save my money.
Is that crazy?
I'll buy this, though.
Why not?
Maybe donate a little bit.
I'm gonna donate a tiny amount.
There we go, 241.
I like it.
And...
Do we look for a secret room?
I think we do.
I have seven bombs, right?
I think there is one right here.
Shit.
Okay, where else could it be?
Um...
It's not on the right wall here, because that I already exploded with an enemy.
Maybe it's all the way down here.
Also, here's the pool.
Okay, nothing.
Let's try here.
Okay, that's it.
I'm not gonna try anymore.
I wanna keep some of my bombs on me.
Oh, one thing I could do...
Is to bomb the shit out of these.
That's always a good idea.
Massive?
Okay, well...
I think that was worth trading one bomb or two bombs technically for four coins.
Alright, now we'll leave.
So far, this run has been stellar.
Stellar, absolutely immaculate.
Let me sip my coffee before I start this boss.
I like that we can see the syringe in my left arm.
That's messed up.
Let's go.
Okay, so it is caves one.
And we can actually get in here.
I'm gonna do it.
Lovely.
Ah, wait, okay, so it's always this room.
What is going on here?
What is, what is happening?
You want coins?
I have coins.
Take some coins.
Please.
Hey!
Holy shit, that's huge!
Thanks, brother!
Oh my god.
That was actually amazing.
Okay, I like that.
I like it a lot.
Okay, these guys are danger.
Let's see here, what is the best way to do this?
Probably to...
Wait, is my guy killing him?
Oh, no way!
Come on!
Oh my god, it's amazing!
Let's go down here.
Get him!
Oh, that's a little bit trouble.
How on earth am I gonna kill these guys?
I'm gonna bomb one of them.
There we go.
That's how you do it.
That was my last bomb too.
But these guys are honestly some of the hardest enemies in the game.
You gotta deal with them in specific ways.
There we go.
Noted the rocks, beautiful.
This way.
Uh oh.
A mini Duke of Flies.
Oh, he exploded, huh?
Very good.
Ah, but wait, wait, wait.
This we can definitely get in.
Yes!
Lovely.
And we have a challenge room that is open.
Why is it open?
Let's think about this.
Maybe it's related to my demon meter.
In the sense that if I have taken a demon deal, then this opens.
Huh?
I mean, look at the color of it.
It does look a little demonish, right?
So I could say that is...
Oh no, I don't have a key.
Oh well.
I'll come back later, I guess.
Please don't close on me.
Don't close on me.
Oh, I got hit.
I didn't even see that projectile.
I have pretty good damage.
You can't complain about the damage.
Oh, this guy up here is going buck wild.
Battery.
Oh, I should have let my familiar kill him.
Let me get in close.
I'm going to risk it.
For a biscuit.
Did he get him?
No.
Something else killed him.
Abba, wait!
He can't heal blue hearts.
It's only red hearts, of course.
That didn't make any sense.
Oh, that was close.
Almost got hit.
Oh man, I'm lacking keys.
It's kind of a problem.
Got good bombs, though.
Great amount of bombs.
Oh god.
Good.
I feel like I am on another level today.
It's hard to explain how, but I'm like, locked in, you know?
I feel like I've taken speed, even though I haven't.
And even though I don't know what that feels like.
But it feels like it.
Do we take the boss now?
I think we do.
Why not?
It's Vistula.
Oh wait, he turned into smaller ones.
You know what?
Let's bomb the shit out of them.
They're gonna run into the poison and things are gonna take care of themselves.
Okay, the poison doesn't last that long.
Oh, something hit me.
Mom's coin purse spawns four random pills in pickup.
Okay, this can either be really good or bad.
Wish me luck.
There it is.
You wished me luck.
And...
There we go!
Should we keep going?
We're already in the wind.
At this point, at the casino, you should stop.
But I'm gonna keep going.
Okay, that's not too bad.
Come on, come on.
Yeah!
I'm a winner.
Mom?
I hear you.
Stop it, Mom.
Do we have more Mom hands?
Dark matter, let's see.
More damage, chance for tears to apply fear effect.
Chance increases with luck, that's pretty good.
We have good luck.
Too spooky for me.
Plus five half-tier.
Shot speed applies fear to enemies in close range.
And goat head guarantees all devil deals appear and remain open.
That one is kind of an investment in the future.
But that also has kind of a drawback, which is...
I would have to make use of the deals, right?
I only have three hearts right now, so I would need to find more health.
If this is something I want.
This is immediate, you know, this is something good right now.
It's really good, actually.
This one is also really good.
Shot speed is also something I really like.
Apply fear to enemies.
Honestly, I could...
Man, we're gonna end up with only two hearts if we do this.
I think I'm gonna go for the definite improvement here, which is the damage.
I feel like I would need more hearts for this to be worth it with the goat head.
That's my reasoning there.
Alright, we're going back, though, because we still have things to find.
I need to find a key real bad.
Like, I can't even tell you how bad I need a key.
In fact, I need two keys.
Can we maybe destroy some rocks and find keys or something?
That's what I really need.
I can't even go in there and open the chest because I don't have a key.
Uh-oh, uh-oh.
What the...
Wait, why am I... Oh, my tears are black now because of that effect.
That's pretty cool.
I only have one bomb.
This ain't good.
Yeah.
Man, I can't believe we're leaving behind a shop with all this money and the treasure room.
It's driving me crazy right now.
Give me that.
Man, that's just... Oh, I hate it!
Hold on, I'm gonna do a crazy gamble here.
I think the secret room is here.
But then I can maybe get to the treasure room from the sides.
You ready?
Here we go.
Oh!
Oh, my goodness!
Look at me go, baby!
Look at me go.
We even got the poopy butt.
Very nice.
I like that one quite a bit.
That was so clutch.
We're gonna do this as well to get inside the shop.
Man, I'm gaming.
That was actually crazy.
Okay, we got pills.
Unidentified, though.
That is a risk.
I think the safe option here is to go for the heart.
Booster packs.
I don't have any cards, so that could be good as well.
I'm not sure here.
Let's take this one, though.
Another bomb is not too bad, either.
Then we have 15 left.
We could go for the booster pack.
Or this one.
What could that give us?
That could be keys.
We need...
Oh!
Baby!
You know what?
We're gambling so hard today, I believe in the white pill.
Okay, I needed to be brought down a little bit.
You know, I was all the way up on cloud nine.
Now we're on cloud four, approximately.
Donate the rest, because I have a bad feeling about what's gonna happen now.
It's okay.
Our luck had to run out at some point.
Remind me what this poopy butt does?
Giant fart that poisons, petrifies, knocks back, and deals 100 damage.
Wow.
Destroys obstacles and breaks open doors.
Really?
Wait, wait.
Oh, wait, but it has a lot of battery charges.
I see.
Okay, so it's not something I can just use all the time.
Got it.
Dude, I was gaming on this floor.
You can't tell me I wasn't.
If we look, you know, away from the last part with the white pill, I was doing great.
See, that's closed now.
Why?
Is it closed?
Enemies?
Show me the enemies.
No enemies.
Uh-oh.
I freaking hate those spiky boys.
Nice.
I'm poor now.
I spend all my money.
It's not that hard to dodge.
When they start chasing me, that's when shit hits the fan, you know?
I got hit somehow by something.
Why are these not turning off?
Come on now.
Oh, man, we can get in here.
Worth it.
Getting that money back.
Wow.
Wait, was that ten?
Or was that five?
I couldn't count.
I can't count.
I'm not sure how much I just got, but it's a lot.
I need more red hearts so I can actually benefit from this guy healing, you know?
I need flying here.
I don't have that.
I think what I need is a little bit of extra tears.
Wow!
Uh, I could go in there.
It's hella risky, though.
I think I'm gonna... I'm gonna go in there.
Mega... Oh, he jumps, right?
Like, he jumps a lot.
Alright, he does that right.
Okay.
Okay, okay, here he comes.
Here he comes.
Oi, yo, yo, yo.
You gonna jump again?
You gonna jump again.
Oh, man.
Oh, damn, no health, though.
Too bad.
Good amount of range, though.
I'll say that.
1 HP, yikes.
I need to time this correctly.
Oh, okay, you don't want to run straight across, I guess.
Dude, I'm in trouble here.
I gotta go back and heal.
Oh, my God.
Oi, yo, yo, yo.
We're gonna use the Poopy Butt ASAP here.
Oh, that's a... coin.
Okay.
Yeah, definitely using that here.
Uh, we got an unknown pill.
Pretty fly?
That's good.
Nice!
We got Lucky.
We got a blue boy.
No problem.
I'm scared.
Oh, he was feared.
I see.
I got no bombs.
Fuck, that's tempting, but I can't do it.
I can't do it.
Because I will literally die.
Oh, that's nice.
Whew.
What did I get?
Puberty.
Oh, okay.
Very good.
I need more Soul Hearts.
That'll be fantastic.
Whoa!
Nice.
They're still shooting.
And we got money too.
What was that one?
Consumes a Red Heart container.
Uh, no, no, no, no, no, absolutely not.
I'll take this.
The world!
Ah!
Secret room spotted.
Okay.
I feel like I should donate a little bit, because this run...
I'm not feeling fantastic about it.
Oh, wait, before I do.
What is that?
Oh.
Ah, man, that is a shitty item.
I mean, it's good, but...
Compared to what I have...
No.
I'll keep my poopy butt.
Donate.
Oh, it broke!
Okay, that was that, huh?
Feels good, though, to know that I donated everything I could.
Time for the secret room.
Also, let's check if this door is open now.
It's not.
Okay, so, you know what I think?
I think, uh, when you enter the floor...
You cannot change the situation with that room.
Either it's open from the beginning or it's closed.
Like, it will not open later on or close later on.
It is something that happened before this floor that determines whether or not it's open.
Or not, you know?
That's my last bomb.
Evil flames?
This was a shitty room.
Can't even bomb the guy.
That's too bad.
Uh, where's the boss?
Up here.
Let's leave.
Man, we gotta find some more healing.
Oh, whoa!
I mean, some extra hearts.
I couldn't do it.
I have to wait a bit.
Oh, man.
Scary stuff.
Alright, it's necropolis now.
And we got the poopy butt.
I can do this.
Oh my god!
They had lasers.
That's very unexpected.
He's feared though, right?
Yeah, okay.
Oh my god!
I lost my blue hearts.
Big problem.
Gaming.
Nice, nice, nice, nice, nice.
Just kill him.
Good.
I needed those.
Oh god!
Yeah, just stay over there, that's good.
Let's go this way.
Okay, let's see.
Is that worth it?
One...
I need a bomb and a key to get in there.
Let's do it.
Huh?
Safety scissors.
Diffuses troll bombs and converts them into bombs.
Oh, that's nice.
Very cool.
I don't want to accidentally touch these.
Good.
Oh, this shit.
I should have saved my poopy butt for this.
That's not that bad actually.
It's okay.
Oh, wow.
Another pretty fly.
Pretty fly.
I mean, I am just the master of flies at this point.
You can call me the Duke of Flies.
Wait, he's still shooting.
There we go.
That could have been a troll bomb, I guess.
We wouldn't know.
Okay.
Let's go north.
Ooh, no thanks.
I'm kind of in trouble here.
Oh, nice!
Thank you, buddy.
My leech is doing work.
Wheel of Fortune spawns a slot machine.
Okay, what's this?
Pause freezes all enemies in the current room for up to 30 seconds.
The freeze effect ends early if Isaac fires a tear.
I feel like that is just putting off the inevitable anyway.
This is an item I've never tried.
Let's try this.
Shielded tears.
Lost contact.
Oh, we lose shot speed though.
That's okay.
Tears collide with and destroy enemy shots.
Oh, pretty cool.
And we also have money to use the Wheel of Fortune.
That's the one with the texts, right?
Let's see.
Oh no, that's the one-armed thief.
Wonderful.
I do have one lock.
Wait a sec, before I do this, how about we check out the shot that's right over here?
Oh, spider mod!
What's this?
BOGO bombs?
No, no, no.
An unidentified pill.
Don't tempt me like this, but I will take this.
I will take that.
Hell yeah, we're going to be able to see the HP of enemies.
What else did it do?
Random status effects.
Chance to spawn a battery or blue spider when clearing a room.
Dude, I'm going to have so many familiars and stuff following me around.
Also, this one is totally needed.
I'm going to save up for that pill because I want it.
And I'm actually going to go up and blow this up.
Wonderful.
I could also get in there.
I should have done that before I took the blue heart, I guess, but it's okay.
Oh!
Very nice!
All right.
Six coins?
We can actually afford the pill now.
We know it can't be a health down pill, right?
Because we already got one of those, so that's huge.
What other bad pills are there?
I guess there's ranged down and all kinds of stuff, but let's see.
Fuck.
Okay, well, I guess we were running a little too fast anyway.
It's good to slow down a bit, you know?
Do not overexert ourselves.
That's a rule you need to follow.
Oh, wow.
So, wait, I need to remember now that my shots actually destroy their shots.
Dude, seeing their health bars is so weird!
I can't get over that.
That's so weird.
All right, he's going to jump.
Oh, they all died.
Okay, good.
Oh, we can get to that.
Oh, we're not done yet.
Hold on, I need to think here.
Yeah, definitely go back.
Ah, here's the thing though.
We have a blue heart right now.
We may not have that later.
I'm going to do boss now and then come back afterwards.
We may even get health upgrade from the boss, right?
I never remember what these bosses do.
But those moving spiky boys are going to be a problem.
Locking in, locking in.
Oh, shit.
Good, good, good, good, good.
Dodging, dodging, dodging.
Fuck!
Nice.
That's good, I guess.
We got to go back and heal.
Do we not have a...
You know what, I don't trust myself to actually do that without taking damage.
I'm going back for the other heart.
Oh, yeah, we have a heart.
Nice.
Very good, very good.
Okay, let's see.
No!
Dear God!
Okay, okay.
That was scary.
Uh-oh.
Get him!
Is he stunned?
What happened there?
Oh, it's ghosts.
I'm really scared here.
Okay, one is down.
Nice.
Uh, no tinted rocks that I can see.
We have one poopy butt charge in case we need to use it.
We also have five monies.
Oh, that's a friend.
I thought it was an enemy.
That's massive.
Thanks.
Now we move on.
I will say, though, this run is not looking good simply because we just don't have the HP.
We've been very unlucky with finding damage items only.
Okay, let's go.
Next floor.
Is this mom?
It is.
Okay.
Man, we need one heart more for the mom, I think.
I'm not going to be able to do it on...
Well, I think at the time we reach mom, one heart.
That's going to be trouble.
Yikes, okay.
Very good.
Mom.
He just killed mom.
Did y'all see that?
That was cool.
Very nice.
Dude, I feel like the fact that my projectiles destroyed their projectiles is actually so massive.
And I haven't really gotten used to that yet.
Dude, I'm freaking dying here somehow.
Oh, it's you.
Well, that goes my blue hearts.
It was nice knowing you.
Oh, no.
Wow.
Okay, good.
I'm looking for tinted rocks.
I'm seeing none.
I am seeing a dick spot, though.
I got bombs!
We could blow these fools up.
Let's do it.
Too bad.
Hey!
Massive.
Okay, okay, all right, cool.
I was about to say, why is that not a real bomb, but then it turned into a real bomb and everything was good.
Dude, I am actually the best.
I can't even describe the skill levels that I'm displaying here right now.
Insanity.
Blow you up.
Okay, where's the treasure room?
Oh, my God.
Wowie.
This is getting a little scary.
I should be safe as long as I keep shooting, right?
Are you there?
Let me look for rocks.
I see none.
We got yellow poops.
Yeah, let's go.
Dude, is my familiar shooting through the rocks?
That's kind of awesome.
Oi.
You know what else?
Having the health bars on is actually so helpful for me because I know which ones are the enemies and which ones are my familiars.
I feel like that should be a standard setting.
VR goggles?
Tech X laser ring tiers.
Replaces tiers with charged laser rings?
Damage in size of the rings increases with charge amount.
Whoa.
All right.
Not sure if it's good, though.
We'll see.
Okay.
That's evil flames.
Why is the coin right on them?
Leave.
Oh, man.
We lost our blue hearts.
I'm going to get in there.
Huh?
What did I just get?
Oh, a black heart!
Yeah!
That's massive.
Very good.
Oh, we actually have a store.
I missed it.
Don't get hit, don't get hit.
Oh, my God.
Plus one lock?
I'm going to take this and the blue.
This one is...
No, it's an active.
Okay.
Let's see if I can get more money.
This is so weird.
I don't know if I like this, actually.
Oh, nice.
What's this one?
We don't know.
Definitely taking that.
Definitely taking this.
Lock.
And what else?
I think I'm going to buy this card as well.
Correct me if I'm wrong, but actually don't correct me.
But if I go to the next floor, I don't think there's going to be any more shops.
So money is going to be useless.
Buy it.
The sun!
That's actually really good!
Holy shit!
The sun, baby!
I'm not going to take that coin.
It's too risky.
Wait, remind me what the sun does?
Isn't that the one that heals me, deals damage, and also reveals everything?
We are so ready for this.
Oh, that is... Oh, right.
I forget I have these weird tears now.
Wait, why is this looking like this?
Things look weird.
Oh, man, what is that even?
You got to keep moving.
All right!
Not bad... Oh!
I feel like that is a bad idea.
This is going to be that huge room where bosses are going to spawn infinitely.
Yeah.
Oh, I get a black heart from this.
Sick.
I'm actually going to do... What is my scissor thing again?
Okay, I don't like that actually.
I'm going to take this.
Taste like burning.
Increase chance of finding bombs.
I don't think I'm going to go in there.
It's too risky, man.
I need to keep moving.
Ooh, man, I'm so tempted.
Here's the thing.
Last time I went in there, I had a mechanism...
where I could keep healing, right?
I technically do now as well with my familiar, but I only have one red heart.
This is a problem.
But I do have these tears.
I'm going to do it.
Oh, right.
It's only when I... Okay, I see.
Okay.
Tiny planet.
Tears fire in a circle?
Wait, what?
No.
Toxic shock.
Poisons all enemies...
at the start of each room dealing damage.
I mean, that's pretty good because I'm immune to poison, right?
Destroyed enemies also leave behind a small creep pool that can damage other enemies.
So when I pick one of these up...
this is going to start the event.
I'm not really intrigued by any of this, honestly.
Maybe this one to get conjoined?
Up to two out of three.
But it's not that great.
This one sucks ass.
This one is pretty bad as well.
You know what?
I'm out of here.
That's right, I'm leaving.
Okay, so now it's not the heart yet.
That's the next one.
The heart is the final.
Look, it's open here.
I'm doing it.
Empty.
I'm not sure I like this new tier format...
that I have.
Okay, the fact that it hits multiple enemies is pretty good, I guess.
Maybe it is okay.
Not too bad.
Oh, man.
Okay, it is pretty good.
It's pretty good.
I do enjoy it.
Yes, yes.
The damage is very good when there's multiple enemies or big enemies.
Oh, my God.
The thing where it sucks, though, is that my shielded tiers are actually worse now...
compared to before, because before I could just have a stream and I would be safe, you know what I mean?
This one, I'm unsafe any time I charge.
That's the problem.
Oh, wait, I shoot through things as well.
That's actually pretty massive.
Open up.
This way.
I also have the Poopy Bot and the Sun on standby.
All right, that was pretty nice.
This one's gonna make only red chests appear.
I don't like that at all.
Because we've got money.
What was the deal here?
Right, okay.
I got 15 bombs.
We can start looking for secret rooms.
No problem.
I thought it was gone!
I thought it was the creep, man!
God damn it.
Fuck me.
That thing respawns so fast.
Oh, my God.
Kill him.
Nice.
Things are getting a little dicey here.
I need to have a faster charge.
That's what I need.
I had to use it.
This room scared the be- Jesus out of me!
AHHH!
It's over!
Yeah.
A room like that, it's just over.
Guys, I gotta take a piss.
I'll be right back.
Dear diary, today I died.
I was killed by a frickin' INANIMATE OBJECT!
Feels really bad, yo.
Let's do some challenges.
Let's see this.
Let's start from the top.
Pitch black.
I'm assuming we're not gonna be able to see shit.
Okay, Curse of Darkness.
And I guess, okay, so we default to Isaac when we do this?
Wait a minute.
I see two things on the left.
I see a trophy with a red cross and mom's feet.
And on the right side, we have a heart.
Oh, that means I can't see my hearts and...
The darkness, I guess?
I'm not actually sure what these symbols mean.
I guess we'll find out.
Does it mean that mom's foot can come down at any time?
Because if that's the case, then I'm in trouble.
Um, okay.
Nothing in there.
I mean, the darkness is not too bad.
But it will be bad in rooms where there's a lot of enemies shooting long-range projectiles, right?
Laser, specifically, would be a problem.
And if I'm Isaac, I start with three hearts, right?
So I can definitely go in here.
Yeah, this room is already looking pretty bad.
I can barely see anything.
Okay, there we go.
Not gonna donate.
Absolutely not.
Oh,
we got a treasure room here that's huge.
Let's look for rocks.
Nothing.
It follows me around blocks after ten hits, glass breaks, and Isaac gains fire rate for the floor.
But I mean, is that really gonna happen very often?
I guess we'll find out.
Good.
That was actually so well aimed.
The Duke of Flies.
The way I see the challenges, though, is kinda...
Like, I can barely play the game without having an extra challenge on top of it.
So is it really the best idea to do the challenges?
The challenges feel like something that someone who's already done with the game goes for, you know?
Oh, the game is too easy.
I need more challenge.
That's totally not me, you know?
Like, I'm in the shit when it comes to just a normal difficulty.
At least this guy's easy.
Oh, you bastard!
I can't believe he actually got a hit in on me.
That's embarrassing.
Oh, are we not done?
Oh, okay.
Oh, I hate this item.
We got no devils or anything?
Moving on.
Maybe I can see my health now.
Unless these stay across the... Oh, wait a minute!
It's a very short...
Look it up there!
There's only six floors?
What the hell?
Okay, so it looks like everything stays regarding the curses.
Oh no, he's camouflaged.
Brother.
Okay, nice.
The devil!
Wait, what was that?
Plus two damage for the room?
Pretty good.
Look at the rocks.
Nothing.
Aha!
Oh, that one is... I believe that's the one that gives my bombs a faster fuse.
So I don't like that very much.
I do like this though.
Even got a coin out of that jar.
Yeah, coin here.
Something's gonna pop out of the floor?
No?
Man, this is gonna take a while to clear this room.
I actually have so much range, I don't even need to be going back and forth.
Except against this guy, I do.
Not bad.
Oh, we got a pill.
Wait, I'm not even sure what that does.
What does that even do?
Hey, you might blow me up up here so I can maybe find a secret room.
Thanks.
I killed him.
What the... Huh?
Disco!
Oh my god.
What is happening?
Okay, you know what?
Call on the devil!
I need your support.
Here, enjoy.
Nice!
Okay, we got him.
No idea what's happening here.
I've never seen this before.
Item multiplier?
Doubles the bombs.
Oh, that's good right now.
I'll use it.
The underwear.
Yeah, that's good.
Oh wait, it spawns flies because they're filled with poop?
Is that the...
thing they're trying to say?
I could go for the boss.
I have not found the treasure room yet though, so I will go for that first.
Holy god, there's a lot of flies here.
Dude, this guy is dodging like a maniac.
What's that?
Mitre.
Okay, 33% chance of converting red hearts drops into soul hearts.
Yeah!
Oh, I like that effect!
Look at that!
I look like one of those clocks people in America would have on their walls in the 70s.
You know what I mean?
Looks exactly like that.
I have a feeling, right here.
No, wait, we already found the secret room.
I'm kind of a dumbass right now.
But what about second secret room?
Boom!
You know, when I do that, I really should make it a habit to...
always do it near a wall, like I just did.
Just in case we find a secret, right?
Okay, does this heal me?
It doesn't.
Okay, so...
I think I have three red hearts right now, nothing else.
I don't even think I have a blue heart.
Man, I need more damage or attack speed or something, because this is not going to hold up in court.
Time for the boss!
What a clean-looking map, huh?
I will say, though, the challenge so far feels easier than...
the non-challenge.
It's kind of ironic.
Oh, I thought you were going to charge me.
Yeah, he always shoots when he whistles.
Motherfucker!
I'm too slow!
I thought he was going to charge me.
Oh, the glass of milk broke!
That's cool.
Oh yeah, and I gain attack speed, right, for that?
That's very noticeable, actually.
Nice!
Uh, speedball... I mean, sure.
No devils, okay.
We're just moving on.
Speedball!
Isn't that a drug?
I think that's an expression for taking drugs.
Okay.
We got worms.
The glass of milk just absorbed a little bit there.
That was actually kind of close.
Holy...
Nice.
That was a tough room.
I could get in there, but I'm not gonna.
Uh-oh, you don't want to split them up like that.
What do we have?
Shot speed!
I like that one a lot.
Now we just need more tears.
What?
Oh, I hit the spikes!
Oh, man.
How do I even get in there?
I guess when you fly, there's no other way.
It hurts.
No, it doesn't.
Taking damage fires a ring of ten large tears and grants a stacking tear.
Stat bonus for the current room.
These ring tears leave bloody creep on the ground.
I don't even know.
The milk!
Oh, we now have very good attack speed for the rest of the floor!
Okay.
Man, I need healing.
I think.
I have 3.5 damage.
Like, this is horrible.
Oh.
Didn't even see you there.
Good.
Getting pretty unlucky with the poops.
Oh, no.
I'm doing no damage, man.
Come on!
I have good range.
Okay.
I'm actually gonna get that.
The hermit.
Teleport to the shop.
Why not?
Wait, that's not a shop.
What the heck, man?
What do you mean?
Maybe that means there are no shops in this game mode.
Crap.
Oh, man, that's evil!
Open up wide!
Very good.
I say we just go for it.
Larry.
There's two of them!
Uh-oh.
I thought you were gonna come over here!
Okay, here.
Yeah, you like that?
I mean, if they just stay over there, then I'm happy.
Okay, never mind.
We should probably clear some of this poop.
Okay, one of them down.
He's kind of locking himself in with the poop.
Very good.
Stuy?
More damage?
More range?
But only for one eye.
Yeah, one of my eyes is closed now.
But, I mean, call me crazy.
Isn't this the exact same attack that I had before?
Like, in terms of the amount of tears I'm shooting?
I don't understand this eye business.
Move on.
Okay, so I wonder if this is now mom, and then the very last is gonna be the heart.
Or if the very last is mom.
We'll find out.
Man, I was low on HP then!
I've picked up two full hearts.
Want to buy damage.
Flying tomatoes.
Pomodoro.
Aw, man.
Aw, fuck off.
Okay, good.
Bit of healing.
Oh, I really want that.
I can get it.
Brother!
How annoying is that?
Definitely eating pills.
Yep, eat them all.
Thank you.
Yay!
I feel like coins are useless.
There's no shops.
I'm gonna go for this chest.
Okay, then.
This is not good.
These enemies fucked me up.
What the frick is happening here?
Oh, it's the pill?
The pill is having effects.
Everyone's moving faster, not just me.
Wow.
Damn.
Come on.
What is that?
An analog stick.
360 tears.
Allows firing tears diagonally?
If using a gamepad allows full 360 degree aim.
Oh my god!
That's frickin' awesome!
Okay, that's actually kind of huge.
I'm probably not gonna get used to it.
Aw, I'm caught!
Aw, that was close!
Come on!
Shoot me here, actually.
Come up here and shoot me.
I need to open secret paths.
No?
What about over here?
This is so weird.
Alright, then.
I have no idea how much HP I have.
If you think about it, though, it shouldn't matter.
Because you should play your best no matter what, right?
How many hearts you have?
Oh god.
Fuck me fast!
Very good.
Oh!
Wait, they died?
Wow.
I still have 3.5 damage, dude.
Not a single damage increase.
That's wild.
Nice.
Would love to find a donation machine.
I can give this money to something.
Oish!
Okay.
Oh my god.
Oish!
Thank god they didn't use lasers.
Oh god, healing.
Very good.
Alright, that's perfect!
And that's the boss!
Let's go for it!
Oh no, this guy is tough!
Bomb him!
I've got no more bombs.
Oh, I have to remember I can do this now.
Okay, I'm gonna jump now.
Oh god.
He's jumping, he's jumping.
Dude, that was freakin' clean!
Whoo!
That was aw- Oh, we get damage!
Finally!
Things are looking up.
They are looking up quite a bit.
Now, do we do this though?
What the f- Bro, fuck off with that!
I'm not even gonna consider that.
No thanks.
I'll take this W and move on.
Okay, let's do this.
I got 55 coins!
I need this glass of milk to break.
I feel like I'm reliant on that.
Bar!
What the- They got stuck on each other!
Man, I'm not doing anything!
There we go.
Finally.
Uh oh.
We got King Poop!
Just gonna play Space Invaders here.
I think I'm hitting some- Yeah, I'm definitely killing things.
Wait, are they stuck in that center island?
Ah, kinda.
Alright.
Aw, thanks.
Great reward.
Wait, what is that one?
He's doing creep.
All man, me shooting diagonally against these guys is... Chef's Kiss.
Get him.
Diagonal shots, baby!
Very nice.
Wait, how am I gonna get to you?
Oh, can I heal?
Oh, I'm full HP, that's nice.
Good to know.
Bro, come outta there!
Dude, what is this?
Thanks.
That's huge.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Beautiful.
Let's go up here.
I've got plenty of healing though if I need it later.
Nice.
Solid.
Uh, poison's all enemy?
Yeah, sure, whatever.
I like the poison.
And it also, uh...
Ah, wait, wait, wait.
That's not gonna damage me though, is it?
The creep.
It does say enemies, but I mean, who the frick knows?
Nice, we got the milk destroyed?
That's huge.
Just one more.
Lovely.
Man, things are going pretty well.
All things considered.
Oh, god.
I say that too early.
Gym.
I think we just go for the boss.
Yeah.
The bloat.
Oh, if he just keeps going...
Huh?
Alright, he's little followers.
I'm in trouble.
Kill him!
Oi, oi, oi!
We gotta heal up here.
Uh, the soap, more...
Oh, that's good.
That's really good, actually.
Here's the thing.
Uh, we're gonna take this.
We're gonna check this out.
We got someone here!
Oh!
Close.
Sulfur, Grant's brimstone for the current room.
Ah, okay.
Activating twice in the same room, Grant's a more powerful version.
Balls PhD.
Converts most good pill effect into bad pills.
Identifies pills before.
Consuming any stat down pill will also grant a permanent damage up.
Consuming most other pill types will also spawn a black heart.
I think this is better for me.
I need damage.
I'm taking it.
Bad trip.
Deals one heart damage to Isaac.
Turns into a full health pill when at one health or less.
I'm gonna take this, but I'm not gonna use it yet, because I don't know how much HP I have, so I'm gonna go back and heal up first.
Okay, I'm full HP.
I gain more damage.
I think I am at two red hearts and...
one black.
No, and half a blue one as well, I think.
Okay.
Let's see here.
Wow.
Why are they suddenly moving so fast?
Need a donation.
Oh, arcade!
We have so much money!
Dude!
Only one guy taking money, though.
The rest is a scam.
Oh.
Random pills.
Bad trip.
Deals one heart, turns a full health pill.
Right, that's the same.
Minus one range.
Oh, this one adds damage.
I think that's good for me.
I have a lot of range already.
Minus one luck, plus I like that as well.
Sponsored.
Oh, I see how this works now.
It will actually say on the description when it gives me more damage.
I thought it just was every bad pill is now giving me more damage across the board, you know?
This one is also good.
I'm gonna take this, but I'm not gonna use it until I have a heart ready somewhere.
And I may also blow up.
No, I can't blow up, damn.
Okay.
Let's go.
Oh, no.
Not this room!
I'm not going that way.
Oi, oi, oi.
Stop jumping!
Jumping jacks.
Running my life.
Okay.
I'm very low HP, I think.
No, I'm not.
What?
Oh, I guess my black heart didn't disappear yet.
So I'm actually gonna do this.
Yeah.
Nice.
Oh, I'm in trouble here.
I'm in the fucking corner.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
We need more healing.
Let's go back.
I don't know if this will heal us, because we do have a couple black hearts, but yeah, okay.
We are actually full on red hearts, it seems.
I think the laser killed Mom.
Nope, nevermind.
I want another arcade.
Dude!
This is crazy.
Can we heal now?
Nope.
I think we're still on a black heart, then.
Because I had two black hearts, right?
Wait, what?
Did I already clear this room?
I'm so confused right now.
What is happening?
Cricket set.
Oh, that's a lot of damage!
Yo!
There we go!
All right!
That's what I needed.
That's a crazy amount of damage, just like that.
But I don't know how much HP I have now, this is the problematic part.
I gotta go back and heal, and at least attempt to heal.
Okay, now I could heal, okay.
Man.
That means I'm probably at two red hearts now.
Maybe one and a half.
Okay, so I'm at two red hearts, then, because I can't pick that up.
Check the rocks.
All right, I think it's time.
It's mom time!
Oh, fuck me.
Oh my god.
I think I'm pretty much dead here.
No, we did it!
Eyedrops.
More tears increases fire rate from Icyx's left eye.
What's this?
The rune of Hagalas!
Ey!
Okay, challenge completed!
I hope it's gonna say that it's completed in here now.
Yeah!
Okay, that's kinda...
Ooh, that feels good.
I like that little, uh...
Yeah, okay, that's nice.
Let's try Hybrow.
What is that?
I'm a little poop man.
And I have a dildo as an active?
Flush transforms all normal enemies in the room into poop obstacles?
Does not affect most bosses or mini-bosses, but instantly kills certain bosses.
What?!
Ha!
That's interesting.
Instantly kills certain bosses.
E.
coli?
Touching enemies turns them into poop- Oh wait, I have three out of three on Oh Crap!
I'm a fully poop man.
We got tears, less range.
Five bombs, explosions, damage, and concuss all enemies.
We also have a pet- Dude, this is the certified poop man here.
50% chance for destroyed poop to spawn a pickup as well.
Three hearts?
Very low range though.
3.5 damage.
I mean, this looks pretty solid.
Ha ha ha!
I love the sound effect on that.
That's disgusting.
Beautiful.
Oh god.
I should have pushed that into the wall, I'm an idiot.
I need to get used to that.
I still half panic when it spawns, you know?
I wonder what the three out of three on poop man does though.
Like, okay, it transforms me into what I imagine is the character I am now, visually.
But what else?
You know, what else is happening with that?
Maybe it turns me...
Eh, I'm not sure actually.
Uh huh.
I got seven bombs on me!
Dude, I'm rich on bombs.
Oh, I got poop bombs!
How?
Did that just happen?
No treasure room yet though, I gotta find that first.
So this challenge was called highbrow.
I don't know what that expression means, if something is highbrow.
I thought it meant like, fancy.
You know, oh, that guy is highbrow.
Because he's got the suits, and the girls, and the salads, you know?
He's got it all.
Experimental pill.
Lock up, shot speed down.
I mean, that's pretty good, I guess.
I do like getting luck.
The earlier, the better with luck, right?
More chances for that to have an effect.
Thanks.
Eight coins.
Whoa!
This shop is massive!
There's a lot of stuff in the shop.
We can buy a pill?
Ooh, another experimental?
I mean, that's... shouldn't that even out to be a pretty average pill?
Like, on average?
I'm gonna buy this.
Magic fingers.
Consumes one coin to damage all enemies in the room.
Damage scales with tier damage.
Wow.
And we still haven't bought this one.
Kinda wanna save up for it, to see what it is.
I mean, it's a Christmas present, is what it looks like.
So it's probably gonna be a disappointment.
I'm gonna try this poop meter on all the bosses, by the way, just to see which one it works on.
What's up, guys?
That didn't do nothing, huh?
Wow, the bombs, though.
Man, the short range is not good for me.
I feel like the bosses are different.
They spawn bombs when they charge.
Fuck me.
Wow.
More health?
Fuck yeah, I love this item.
Very good.
This one also only has six floors.
Okay, why is there light shafts coming from north?
What does that mean?
I thought maybe it would be related to my angel meter, but it's not, because we're at 0%.
We have a 100% demon.
So I don't know what those light shafts mean.
I see them in certain rooms, other rooms I don't.
Oh, this is gonna be problematic, isn't it?
What I really need, though, is range.
Holy shit.
Let's blow those up.
Spiders and those!
Okay, there you go.
I've had enough of their shenanigans.
Okay, no tinted rocks.
We're moving on.
Oh god, I didn't even see you!
Off screen.
That's just not fair.
Oh, nice.
Very good.
Ah, definitely getting in there.
But let's do it from here.
Oh, is that gonna destroy the two rocks?
Let's check.
It is.
Okay, wonderful.
Very good.
And we're getting rich as well.
Not bad, huh?
I'm gonna blow this guy up.
Alright, this challenge so far doesn't feel like a challenge at all.
What is the challenge part of this challenge, huh?
It's like easy mode.
What is so hard about this?
Got him.
Kinda wanna go in here.
What is that even?
That's new.
Weird room.
I can grab this heart now.
Ah, but that's two, so maybe I save them.
Glowing hourglass.
Rewinds time.
Okay, I know that one.
We actually have enough to buy this.
Ah, but that was the last floor.
Damn.
Never mind.
I gotta go for this one.
Nice.
I could buy that heart, but I'm not gonna.
Should I buy this?
No, I like my current one.
I like the poop effect.
There's a room over here that I missed.
This guy's gonna be hard to kill because of my short range.
That wasn't that bad.
Boss time.
Let's try the poop on him.
The blighted ovum.
Nope.
Didn't work on him.
Oh, his familiar is lasering me.
But man, I'm doing decent damage here.
Really good damage.
Growth hormones.
Fantastic.
That's really good.
Let's go grab that heart.
Let's go check this room up here, just to see if it's actually open or not.
It's not, okay.
But maybe we can get in there.
No.
But wait.
Fuck.
Alright, here's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna go in here and step on the spikes, because we have a double healing heart.
There you go.
Also, our character looks totally messed up.
We look like a little mushroom from behind when we walk like this.
As if there's mushrooms growing on our head.
I'm assuming it's just gonna be normal mom as well at the end.
No heart.
We gained 100% demon.
Okay.
Always on the second floor, we gain 100% demon.
So, let's try and pay attention now.
What is actually going on with that?
Because I don't understand.
Still 100%.
Come here, guy.
I need more range.
I actually want range instead of damage now.
It's more important.
Because damage, we got it.
What's that?
Secondhand increases the duration of status effects.
I don't really have any status effects, do I?
Wait, touching enemies turns them into poop?
I didn't realize.
Huh.
Okay.
I guess I'm gonna take it.
No, wait, wait, wait.
I want this instead.
We gotta complete the poop fantasy, you know?
Come here, dude.
Oh, I should just be standing to their sides.
Also, I haven't seen any tinted rocks at all.
Oh, nice.
Thanks.
Wait, what?
The fly just instantly killed that guy.
It's amazing.
I mean, you know what?
Let's bomb this to get the bomb and check for room.
See, that's smart.
Something like that is what I should be doing more.
No?
There's one guy in here?
Alright.
I'm rich!
Yeah, spider mod!
Let's fucking go!
Boink!
That's mine.
Love this item.
Okay, we got three coins.
We could potentially maybe come back and buy a pill.
Yeah.
I'll be back with more money.
You need to stop that.
He's covering up his own HP bar.
Oh, they have multiple HP bars.
Ah, I see.
Each element has its own HP bar.
I thought it was like a sequential thing, you know?
Where you just damage him and then he loses his things in...
We haven't found the treasure room yet.
Then he loses all his limbs in a certain order, you know?
Kill those spiders.
He's gonna jump on me.
Man, where is this treasure room?
The nice thing about the bars is also that...
Now I know when to take risks and not when to go in closer and stuff.
To actually get the damage in.
Oh my god.
Drive by!
Oh, yeah.
What even is that in there?
Oh, you come back.
I'm definitely getting that.
Thank you.
Come on, let me...
Oh, I gotta destroy it with poop, I see.
Scapular.
When damage down to the last half heart, automatically gain one soul heart.
Uh, when damage?
Okay.
And activate only once per room.
I mean, it's just an item, right?
It's not even an active?
Obviously, I take it.
We got pills.
Are you a wizard?
I forgot what that... Oh...
Oh, no.
That's not good.
That's horrible.
Fuck me.
Ah, man.
Oh, well.
It's not the worst.
It's okay.
Uh, what's this?
There we go!
Some good luck.
Let's try this.
Tears up, speed the... Yeah!
Wait, wait, wait.
Oh, nice!
We reverted!
Are you a wizard?
Has been reverted for some reason.
I wonder if that pill overroaded, or what just happened?
I'm not sure.
Oh, uh, my timer went off.
Let's take a break here.
There we go.
Uh, break for five minutes.
I'll see you in five minutes.
Alright, I'm ready again.
I got my water.
I ate a little bit of dark chocolate.
I cuddled with Jackie for a bit.
I'm ready.
Let's keep going.
This is a fantastic run so far.
There's no way we can mess it up.
Gotta get back into the groove of things here.
Okay, he's up there now.
God, I love these health bars so much.
Like, I can just see the enemies now.
It's so nice.
I feel like health bars should be on by default.
Oi, oi, oi, that was a tough one.
Also, we're at 36% demon now.
I don't know what happened, but we went down in demon.
Maybe it is a timer based thing.
The faster you are, the more chance of a devil you get.
Nice.
I got eight bombs and eight keys.
That's kinda crazy.
Also, what was in that shop?
I gotta go take a look at it.
Oi!
Ho, ho, ho!
Appso-fucking-lutely!
Well, that was an easy pick up there.
Thank you.
What the hell, man?
I'm gonna try the poop mechanism.
Doesn't work.
Oh, god.
Right.
Oh, shh.
Man, this boss is kinda crazy.
I like the little added effects here with the water on the floor.
Because of the poop situation.
Uh, consolation prize.
I mean, there's no reason not to take that, I guess.
What's it gonna give me?
Range, okay.
I would argue my speed is the lowest stat, but okay.
Guess I don't understand numbers.
I would argue one is less than five.
But it's probably like a percentage-based thing where...
You probably can't get to five speed, you know?
There's some kind of waiting going on.
But it's good to have more range, though.
I love these health bars.
So...
It's so easy to see where the enemies are.
It's just...
clean now.
Or before, it's just messy.
Like, okay.
You can make it so that the health bars don't display...
how much health they have, just have a bar on them.
Just to signify which ones are the enemies.
I would love that even, you know?
They don't have to show percentages or whatever.
For me to be happy.
Unidentified?
Okay, I don't know what that actually does.
Wow, that's really bad.
That is really bad for me.
But it is the chance we take.
Ah, this room is ripped.
Honestly, my range is not too bad right now.
Look what I like.
Why not?
That means you get blown up.
Low it up?
Oh, I didn't mean to.
Okay.
I didn't mean to donate!
Aw, man.
Wait, I got hearts out of it, though.
Was that from the donation, or was that from me destroying it?
I couldn't tell.
Wait, I can go heal?
What's the catch?
I can't get it for some reason.
Ah, right, okay.
That was the catch.
These spiders kind of look like robots, similar to my robots.
With the blinking lights.
Ah, there's spikes in there.
I could walk in there and step on that.
Thank God, no laser.
I mean, this is just going really well.
Hey, I thought you were friendly!
Didn't you have a charm on him?
I guess I'm misunderstanding what charm means.
Okay.
I got 11 coins.
Converter!
Oh, man.
We gotta get that.
Yeah.
Thanks!
Thank you!
Convert!
Let's go convert some more, huh?
Oh, there's bombs!
Oh, thanks!
Thanks, bombs.
Okay, so here's the plan.
I'm gonna take this.
Oh, special key acquired.
Before we go into the boss room, I'm actually gonna go back and exchange it so we can try this on the boss now.
Then I'm gonna come back after and move on with the converter.
This is optimized gameplay.
This is what you're witnessing.
Turn into poop!
No?
Wait, what happened?
He got petrified for a bit there.
Random effect, I guess.
No problem.
That was nice.
And this is giving me health!
Okay, you know what?
Since I have so much health already, I'm gonna be honest.
I'm just gonna keep this toilet mechanism.
I feel like I'm good.
I don't need more.
You know?
Whoops.
This way.
One more floor after this and it's mom.
Oh, man.
What is that?
Broken syringe?
Hold on.
Huh?
Oh, it didn't even... Oh, I see.
Now it's there.
25% chance to gain a random syringe effect for the room.
Whoa.
That's good.
Syringes are very good.
I'm slowly casting off my poop man identity here.
Bit by bit.
It's not going too well in this room here.
I'll admit it.
Oh, god.
Oh, I turned him into poop!
That's right.
They walk into me.
What did this one do again?
5% chance of destroyed poops to spawn a pig up.
I mean, I think it's better to walk around with that.
Nah.
Nah, I'm good.
I got lots of pickups already.
Let's focus on syringe effects.
Wow!
That still hit me!
Jesus fucking Christ!
This room is insane!
Holy!
Broken padlock!
Locks can be broken open with bombs.
I don't need that.
I'm assuming it's a trinket.
Pill.
That's not good.
That's not worth it either.
Then again...
I have a lot of bombs, so it's worth it to do this.
Very nice.
Come here, you.
Wow, so any enemy gets to...
That's actually kind of powerful.
Like, just any enemy like that gets turned into poop.
You can make really difficult enemies really easy.
How on earth am I going to kill you, man?
There we go.
No tinted rocks.
Turn into a skeleton.
Thanks for that.
I like that.
Pretty smaller.
Oh!
What?!
He was stuck to me!
I've never seen a bomb this stuck.
Crazy.
Oh god.
Skeletons are no joke.
We should start finding some HP here.
The fool.
Alright.
I don't think I can lose this.
I see.
Actually kind of huge, so we get this healing.
Greed!
Oh my god.
How did I get hit?
That was not good, man.
That was not good.
Ooh, lots of money.
What's next?
The boss should be in here, right?
Oh, that was a coin.
I can't get across here.
Wow!
Can we get an arcade?
Oh, we made it.
Monstro 2.
Oh, okay.
Are you gonna shoot lasers?
What does your animation look like when you shoot lasers?
There it is, okay.
Wait, he only shoots horizontal lasers, or what?
This guy has a lot of HP.
Ah, I was greedy.
I was greedy there.
There was no need to take damage.
Ah, black card.
I mean, okay.
I have so many bombs already.
I don't think I need the matchstick.
Unfortunately, no deals for me.
I am gonna move on.
And now I think it's mom time.
Yes, sir.
These challenges feel easier, man, than normal mode.
Like, non-challenge mode.
I can see forever.
Oh, that's good.
That's really good.
I could go in there.
I'm gonna wait and see how much HP I'm gonna scrounge up here first.
Oh, no.
Holy...
Oh...
I don't need coins and all that, honestly.
I'm leaving it.
I'll come back if I suddenly need it.
I'm making an executive decision on that.
Oh, secret found, because I can see forever.
That's actually such a crazy pill.
Something opened, somewhere.
Oh, here we go.
Come to me.
Ohoy, massive.
We are so ready for mom.
And look at this, we can even buy that.
Oh, everything's on sale.
Spawns for random pills as well?
Dude.
Oh, that's for 30 seconds.
Okay, so that makes sense.
Taking three gives the adult transformation and plus one health.
Ah!
So that's what puberty does.
Amazing.
This one, we don't know what does.
What is that?
Aww.
I will take a normal heart.
And I'll take one of these hearts.
And I'll take that one.
Spawns a beggar?
Doubles I6 coins?
Ooh.
Let's see if I can get a couple more.
Very nice.
Reveals the map?
Wow.
Doubles the bombs?
Wow, that's going to be a lot of bombs.
Holy shit.
The empress?
What was that?
More damage for the room?
This one doubles the coins.
Ah, plus three speed as well.
Here.
Take my coins.
Hey!
Very good.
How about an item?
Dude, I've never had this many bombs.
There we go!
Amazing!
Wow!
That is so huge.
I'm just going to reveal this map.
It's the last floor, right?
Wait, what?
Oh, I used the wrong one.
Whoops.
Whoops, whoops, whoops.
That was bad.
That was a mistake.
Well, there we go.
That's the map.
We even have a dice room.
Guess I'll buy this.
Give me that.
Okay.
Very good.
Honestly, should we just go for the boss?
No, we're going to find the treasure room and then we're going to go for the boss.
How come the treasure room is not showing up on the map?
Shouldn't that be revealed?
Maybe there is no treasure room here.
These guys actually... I'm starting to feel that I don't have that much damage anymore.
But I have HP.
That was so bad.
Ah,
sponsored blood donation machine.
Dude, I could donate a lot of blood.
It's worth trying, I guess.
Let's see what's in here.
Oh, I used all my money.
No.
I'm curious what happens if I give it like... I don't know, like five hearts, you know?
Because I can afford it now.
Come at me.
Got him.
And we can be sure there's nothing else in this room.
Because we can see forever.
Oh, right, don't step on that.
Still no money.
I want to see the dice room.
If it's six, we're not going to do it.
Dude, my spire is doing respectable damage.
What is it?
My stats sort of...
got balanced or something?
I gained some, I lost some.
Maybe it's like a experimental pill, but times four, you know?
Oh, now we gain the...
Wait.
Is it every room?
Every room I get new stats.
Okay, that's... maybe good, maybe bad.
We'll find out how good that is when we reach the boss.
Okay, stats didn't change now.
Okay, here we go.
Let's try the poop.
That's a veiny leg.
She did not get turned into poop, unfortunately.
Kill this guy.
Dude, we have so many bombs, we should just be bombing shit.
Oh, she pushed my bomb away.
Come on, mom, I need your foot.
This is crazy.
Hey, you like bombs?
Dude, this is so much fun with the bombs.
It's amazing.
Yeah, look at that.
Not bad at all, eh?
That was smooth and clean.
All right.
That's two challenges down.
The rune of Jera.
I didn't get to read it in time.
Let's do one more challenge.
I'm on a roll right now.
The next one is head trauma.
Oh, yeah, I see a head trauma.
Is that a baseball?
Ooh, tiny planet?
Oh...
Oh, okay.
Soy milk.
Oh, that's a lot of tears.
But very little damage.
Iron bar.
A chance to fire concussive tears.
A small...
What the fuck is this?
Did we get a small rug in our...
Oh, that's a beautiful...
That's nice looking.
That's very cool.
All right, we're just going to walk around like this.
All right, spectral tears.
This is going to be interesting.
This is actually so much fun.
All right.
I'm not going to go for that.
What is that sound I'm hearing?
Oh, is that just the music?
Sounded like someone going...
I thought it was maybe me hitting them with these tears.
Give me that.
Yeah, you like that?
You like that?
Too bad I can't pre-charge these from room to room.
Just like I would be able to with Azazel, you know?
Okay.
And that's the boss.
But not yet.
Treasure room first.
Of course.
I could also exchange one bomb for a key.
Question... Oh, we can't get it though.
We don't have enough money.
Good.
Five now, we could buy something.
Or I save my money.
I really want to get this.
Puberty.
Okay, so we need two more and then we gain...
What was it?
More damage, I think?
I'm also going to grab this key.
Oh, look here!
Fuck yeah.
The Empress?
That's going to go wild!
Dude, any damage upgrade we get is going to go buck wild.
Because of the attack speed and the rate of fire here, I don't know, like, oof, man.
I'm going to save it though.
Yeah, you're doing that.
This is fantastic.
This is so much fun.
Wow, that's great.
Cube of meat.
Unfortunately, no deals for me.
I'm going in.
Okay.
Aha!
Look at that!
We got another situation going.
Wow, I just get a key out of that?
I guess I found this too.
That was lucky.
Do I give this guy a key?
I don't think so.
I only have two.
Yeah!
We
got the special...
Listen!
There's a massive door somewhere opening when I pick that up.
And my prediction is I haven't found that door yet.
Like, it's going to be something that I haven't seen, you know?
But it'll come later.
That is so exciting, actually!
Like, what is it going to be?
And look at this.
No, I don't have a bomb!
Oh, too bad.
I'm going to find a bomb.
More keys.
This is so much freaking fun.
I love this challenge.
Oh, God.
Oh, hey!
All right, all right.
We haven't found treasure room yet.
I'll go find it.
Massive.
Ventricle Razor.
That's nothing.
I mean, I kind of want to buy that bomb.
But I need a couple more...
coins for that.
Also, what does this cube of meat do again?
Orbital familiar?
Blocks?
Shots?
Okay.
And it can be upgraded.
Roger.
Okay, one more coin!
Wait, there's no treasure room?
Is that part of the challenge?
I wonder.
Because what the hell?
That's weird.
I'm going to sacrifice a blue heart for this.
That was a waste.
Man, this is the perfect combo to break this with one bomb.
There's got to be like a coin somewhere.
I don't believe it.
Did
I miss one in here?
Oh man, that's heartbreaking.
Maybe we get something from the boss.
Who knows?
It's the haunt.
Oh my god, dude.
Oh!
This is going to be so easy with this.
Whoa!
What the...
This guy's changing his patterns!
That
blue...
That's a lot of tears now!
Twenty?
Wait a minute.
I thought there was a cap on how many I could have there.
How come I have twenty?
That's fucking crazy.
What the hell?
Pentagram.
More damage is good.
Or we need to...
Dude.
Ooh, I could go both.
Oh, that's this.
This...
Hold on.
Let's see if we get a coin, please.
One coin.
Uno coino!
No!
Damn.
Let's do...
Let me see here.
I'm going to take this.
Okay.
Oh man, I really...
Yes.
I'm taking it!
I'm naughty.
I'm the naughty boy.
I'm so naughty.
Let's go.
That's very naughty.
Okay, let's do this.
We got a challenge room.
Obviously, we're going for that.
School bag.
These...
Concuss.
Oh!
Very nice.
We got to find some more HP now.
I messed it up a little bit there.
We got to look for X's now.
All my X's live in Texas.
Where are they?
Where are my X's at?
Whoopsie daisy.
I definitely need more damage though.
I mean, look at this.
It's getting a little ridiculous.
A lack of damage here.
Ah!
What am I doing?
Mistake.
Come on, wake up!
Let's go heal up a little bit.
Also, I wasn't looking out for X's.
Yep, yep, yep.
I could get in there.
Is it worth it?
No, I have no bombs.
Shit.
Okay, but we have a store.
I'm poor!
Okay, I'm not poor anymore.
Let's go to the store.
Tarot card or...
No, I have a pretty good tarot card.
Oh, don't accidentally kill him when I'm close.
Wonderful.
Another one of these!
What the heck?
Okay, let's just go for it.
Pull of phallus?
Good damage though, on this guy.
Can't complain about that.
Beautiful, beautiful.
What happened?
Oh, okay.
A box, spawns one red heart, key bomb, coin pill, card or rune?
Sure.
Two soul hearts!
Not bad.
And a pill?
Even more tears up!
Damn, it's a machine gun!
And this is a bomb, and then we have... what is that?
Callus grants immunity to damage from...
Yeah, very nice!
That's very nice for me.
Do I go back?
I think I do go back.
It's interesting, I don't think there's any treasure rooms in this challenge.
Also, I gotta take another look for dick spots.
Okay, I don't see anything here.
Nothing here, either.
Oh, I can go here.
Do I lose?
Do I use my bomb on that?
Okay, why not?
Oh my god, that was so worth...
Huge!
And we get two bombs in return, wow.
Wow!
Very nice.
Now what?
I think we just leave.
Perhaps go into the store once again, we have eleven coins.
No, you know what?
Let's break our way into here.
I wanna see what's in that box.
Okay, totally worth.
Maybe not totally worth, maybe just worth.
Compost!
Duplicate each blue spider?
No.
Wait, wait, wait, I'm also missing a tarot card, where's my...
Oh, it's probably in the boss room, yeah.
I'm gonna save my money.
So no treasure rooms, but we do have stores in this challenge.
This is the one I need, yep.
That's gonna come in handy against Mom.
Unless I find something even better.
Okay, doors closed, unfortunately.
Jesus Christ.
Oh, thanks for destroying that.
Oh god.
Hahaha, this is so fucking fun.
Yes!
I got so many keys, so let's just go in here.
Oh, spiky boys!
You know what?
No.
Not yet.
Maybe if I lose my blue hearts and I can restore my HP, I'll do it, but...
Really love the concussive effect I have.
And the faster the attack rate, the more chance of concussing.
Mom's purse allows two trinkets to be held.
This one's on sale.
Fourteen coins.
I kind of want Mom's purse.
I'm gonna save it.
I'll need one more coin.
That should be doable.
I'm not seeing any dick spots, either.
I wonder if that's not part of this challenge.
Maybe they cannot appear.
I really hope that's not the case.
Good.
Let's go north.
Why is it not getting hit?
Okay, there we go.
Okay, that's definitely the second now.
Yeah.
I think we need one more.
Unless I'm thinking of last run.
Could be the case.
Here's the boss.
Let's just do it.
I feel good.
It's Peep.
Gonna jump.
We're gonna dodge.
Jumping.
We gotta dodge now.
Got hit by the familiar.
Solid, though.
Solid performance.
Cat of nine tails.
Good.
Any damage I can take.
I'll gladly accept.
We're going back to grab some more stuff.
Potentially look for dick spots.
Dude, we're gonna try and dig.
When we defeat mom.
Let's go south.
Just listen to that machine gun.
Okay.
There's more.
Oh, beautiful.
Twenty-one coins now.
That means we can afford the thing I wanted to buy.
He's concussed.
That is beautiful.
I have so many bombs.
Let's just start looking.
What about here?
Okay, fine.
I have a feeling... Oh, no.
I can't even destroy that.
Okay.
So there was no feeling.
It was a fake feeling.
Let's get this.
And we get cancer.
Dude, twenty... twenty-eight tears.
That's a lot of tears.
It is.
It's quite a bit.
Wowsers.
Uh, wait.
Oh, this is actually worth it.
Okay, moving on.
When is mom?
Let's see.
Wait, we lost demon when we went into this room.
Okay, mom is next time.
Ah, it's open.
Let's freaking go.
Unfair.
Uh, worms.
Yeah.
Oh, come on.
Oh, those are friendly.
Okay.
Dude, the attack speed is crazy.
When you have this much attack speed, does it even matter how much damage you have?
I mean, it matters less and less, I guess.
But it just means whenever I find damage, it's gonna go even harder, you know, when I finally do find damage.
They shot each other.
Like a chainsaw.
Oh, God.
I'm definitely messing up a little bit here, losing my soul hearts.
It's not ideal.
You know what I should have done?
I should have just played around the rocks in the center.
Because I have spectral tears.
How many heals, though?
Damn.
Oh!
Take spot!
Fuck yeah!
Ha ha ha!
Oh, it's one of these rooms.
Oh, I'm gonna be giving hearts.
I don't know if I like that.
Like, I can't even think of one item that would make me do this.
Compass.
No idea.
Bye.
Ooh.
Maybe that one, actually.
Supposedly that kills the mom, right?
The question is, is it gonna do it in this challenge?
That's what I'm worried about.
You know what?
I'm not gonna do it.
Ooh, two heads.
Yeah, I'm not gonna do it.
I will pick up this key, though.
No, I won't.
It's too risky.
I may run into one of the others.
Wait, what?
No, I didn't mean to!
No!
I... Fuck!
Well, I guess we skipped the boss.
That's... sad.
Fuck me.
That was not my intention!
It is what it is.
Dude, I can't wait to activate this Empress card against mom.
It's gonna be crazy.
Uh, ooh, I'm definitely... Oh, that's a tough one, that one.
Maybe.
It's not... Okay, it's not that bad.
Oh!
Let's see the small guy.
No blue hearts.
Holy shit, this room is crazy.
All right.
Get a chest.
Blue hearts, come on.
Too bad.
Oh!
Store, definitely.
Okay, we can buy a blue heart.
And we can also... What's that?
Diplopia?
Duplicates all pickups and item pedestals in the room.
Oh, it's an... Wait, whoa, whoa, hold on.
I can hold two... Actives?
Ah-ha!
Yoink yoink!
Huge.
Spawn red heart pickup stored in a jar.
Ooh, that's actually...
Also pretty good.
Wait, is this free?
Oh my gosh!
I thought it would just duplicate and I still have to pay!
Holy shit!
Whoa!
Okay, that's nuts.
Dude, we're gonna...
Ah-ha!
What the fuck?
That's crazy.
Destroy this.
All right.
Let's go collect some more hearts.
That is insanity.
So we have four hearts in here, it seems.
X-4, it says.
All right, what's that?
The Hank Man... Ooh.
Maybe I'll need it.
Let's keep it in mind.
Very unfortunate that I got hit there.
What was that?
The Devil?
Plus two damage, and this one did.
And some speed.
Oh, this one I have is better.
The Devil.
Yeah.
Okay, I think we're going for it.
Do it.
Wish me luck!
We're gonna pop this immediately.
Fuckin' easy.
Moms, pearls.
Boom, baby.
Oh, wait a minute.
Oh, Lord of the Pit, Grant's Flight, Black Powder, and...
wait.
So here's the thing, what if we dig now?
What if we dig in here?
Doesn't work.
Oh, shit, okay.
Well, we did it.
Three for three!
These challenges, I mean, come on, they're not even challenges!
How about a real challenge?
What's this?
The tank.
That sounds fun.
Oh, you know, no, no, no.
We've done three challenges.
I asked you guys earlier, in the very beginning of the stream, what you wanted to see.
Challenges was one of the big ones, so I did that for sure now.
I had my Isaac run.
People wanted to see Eulith and Magdalene, I think it was.
Oh, Samson, too.
So I'm just going to pick one of them.
Let's go with, um, Samson.
With the Bloodlust, I don't know what it...
Hey, the Windstreak should say plus three, man!
Come on.
Alright, so what is this guy's deal?
Something about Bloodlust.
Okay, let's see, three hearts, 3.5 damage, 5 range.
I think it's a good idea for me to just... This is something I started doing.
Just reading my stats in the beginning to get a feeling for, you know, what I can expect before I even start, you know?
In terms of damage and my capabilities.
Whoa!
What the heck is that?
Eewoz creates a trapdoor to the next floor.
It creates a crawlspace of Eust on top of Lord Decorations.
Are you talking about the X on the floor?
Or what?
It's gotta be, right?
Floor Decorations!
So there's multiple ways to get to the crawlspace?
Or what do you mean?
This is exciting.
We're going to look for an X.
Okay, so interesting that we have an enemy like that here.
I feel like that always comes later.
Oh, he's gonna jump at me?
Come here.
Oh, that's annoying.
Can't get in there.
Let's see if we can find some treasure, huh?
There we go.
Ah, no way that hit me.
What am I gonna get?
Ooh, what is that?
Doctor's remote.
Reusable air strike!
Launches a targeted air strike.
Okay, that sounds cool.
When you say targeted, does that mean I have to target it, or is it automatic targeting?
I guess I'll find out, huh?
Let's go window shopping, because I can't buy anything anyway.
Maybe I can.
Ah, no coins.
What is habit?
We charge just one bar of Isaac's active item.
Terrible.
Can't even get this.
That's so sad.
It's the Duke of Flies.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
This has to be like the easiest boss, right?
Especially for someone like it's Azel.
Just sweeping across and killing all these flies with one fell swoop, you know?
I can't believe I took damage!
I got overconfident.
That was a mistake.
What the hell is this?
Safety pin.
Evil range and shot up.
And a black heart.
Sick.
Very nice.
Let's go.
A hundred percent demon mode.
Okay, I'm gonna fucking glue my eyes to that while I'm playing.
Eyes are glued.
If you had the eye track thingy, you would see my vision down there.
I'm only using peripheral vision right now.
To play the game, I'm kidding.
Not really, but fuck!
Yes, I was using peripheral vision.
I wasn't really looking.
Duh!
Okay, okay.
This guy needs to die.
Can't just sit there spawning spiders.
Stop it.
We lost demon!
I took damage!
But I also took damage in the last room.
So what is it?
Now I'm not sure.
Nice, we got healing.
Always appreciated.
Show me a good item.
What's that?
Infestation two!
Wait, infestation shot?
Killing an enemy spawns a blue spider.
Oh, okay.
Oh, we're gonna get a lot of spiders then.
Not bad.
This way.
Let's try this.
Alright, okay.
Honestly...
Not entire... I didn't even look.
Because I was focused on not getting hits.
I think something came up from above and killed something.
Don't even start.
Get him out of here.
Yeah, you... I turned spiders into allies!
Like, killing them.
I've got so many spider friends.
Oh, I can't die now.
I gotta be careful.
No health anywhere.
Where did I take damage from?
How did I just take damage?
The fuck was that?
Nah, bro.
Oh, no, I'm gonna die in here.
I'm not going in here.
Kill him.
Oh, it is a... okay, it is a manual control.
I see, I see, I saw it, I saw it.
Oh, my God.
Wait, we have nine damage?
Okay, there's something about bloodlust that's doing this.
Uh-oh.
I think I... I think I die here, guys.
Maybe, maybe not.
Oh, the healing.
Clutch.
Uh, look for access in Texas.
I see none.
Keep looking.
Uh, let's go this way.
Also, why am I red?
Oh, I'm blinking.
Nice.
Uh, I think we just... oh, man.
Yeah, we just go for it.
Let's try the airstrike thing against this guy.
Oh,
wow.
Alright, that's a... that's a pretty... that's a pretty good item.
Wowsers.
Let's see what we get here, huh?
Oh!
Evils fire!
Not today, sucker.
But wait, I'm not gonna do anything in here anyway.
Yeah, no way I'm doing that.
Argh, I mean, this familiar is pretty good.
I don't think it's worth it.
No, I always end up with too little HP and then I regret it and I die and end the run, right?
We're gonna play it safe.
New tactics.
Okay.
Uh, oh, question mark.
Shit.
That was kind of lucky there.
Oi, oi, oi!
Oh, sick.
Uh, we're gonna have to rely on our own sense of direction here, which is not good.
Dude, these guys are gonna murder me.
Good thing I have range, though.
Wait, I just...
Oh!
Oh, I think I understand how this bloodlust works.
I took damage and I gained damage.
Ah!
And it can stack or what?
Is that what's happening?
I had like nine before.
Sir, I need you to...
Okay, okay!
Fuck!
He juked me!
Unbelievable.
Oh, I can't even get in there.
Come on, no hearts for me?
Oh, I don't have a map either.
This is...
Okay, do it.
Come on, please.
Judge... oh.
I don't like that.
Oh, wait, I need this.
Uh, you know what?
We can spawn this guy here and come back, I guess.
No, he wants hearts!
Fuck off.
Absolutely not.
Okay, good.
I'm not gonna... oh, I almost ran into him.
Holy shit.
A pill!
Oh, you know what?
Maybe it's too risky.
What if I get like a health down?
Maybe I need to implement a rule.
If I have four or more hearts, then I can take pills.
And again, I mean, what if it's a health up?
Yeah!
Gambling!
Love it.
I'm proud of myself.
What is that black poop anyway?
Oh, right, makes it darker in here?
Yeah, I'm not getting across there.
Oh, man.
I need healing!
Uh, I came from here.
I'm gonna be so lost.
Okay.
Oh, that's new.
Uh, wait, from here.
Sir, wake up!
This guy's annoying!
Okay.
Oh, god, where am I?
Oh, shit!
Dude!
I'm gonna die.
Wow!
I think it's ogre.
Where's my healing?
Um, mom's...
Wait, what did this one do again?
Raise a trap door to the next floor.
Crawl space if used.
Floor decorations.
Oh.
Ah, it's over.
It's over.
There's like, no way.
Didn't even kill him!
Hardest enemies in the game.
Changed my mind.
Somehow, I'm still not dead.
Amazing.
10% chance to heal half a red heart each time you clear a room.
I mean, yeah.
Fuck!
Wait.
Okay.
Oh, my god.
Kill him!
Totally worth.
Half a heart, though.
Half a heart.
Dude.
Oh, I don't know what to do.
I think we're just gonna go for it.
Okay.
Here we go.
Let me think, let me think.
Okay, so I'm gonna use the air strike immediately.
Gertie.
Okay, good.
We hit him with it.
Oh!
I knew I was dead, man.
I knew it.
I can't believe it ended like that.
That was just heartbreaking.
Oh, no.
Hey, we gained damage at least.
Maybe it's the strategy, you know, to take a lot of damage.
Just to gain more damage.
No problem.
Oh, massive.
Okay.
I'm gonna go back, because we need a treasure room.
It's treasure time.
Are you excited, kids?
Oh, look at that.
No bombs, though.
Never mind.
You know what?
I'm not gonna open that, in case we find a treasure room.
Okay, so this one didn't need a key, but, you know, better play it safe.
We got the wiggly boys.
Dude, what the hell?
Okay.
What is this?
Smartfly.
Isaac takes damage, it chases... Okay.
I mean, that kind of...
You know...
It's compatible with my bloodlust.
Boomerang.
Black candle.
Immurity to floor curses!
Immurity to negative effects from certain items.
Dude, this is a really good one.
I don't have money, though.
Maybe I'll get the money.
Get him out of here, he's not gonna jump anywhere.
Any of the tinted rocks?
No, no tinted rocks.
I feel like I haven't seen any of those today.
What is that?
Wishbone.
Chance when taking damage to destroy the trinket and spawn an item from the current room's pool.
Ooh!
Wait, what was the chance?
Oh, okay, only 5% chance.
Oh, Lotus!
I don't have a bomb.
Why is it always happening like this?
It's heartbreaking, man.
They're coming for me!
Wait, one's down?
We got him.
Double Isaac's spot.
Yeah, I wish I had some.
Yeah!
Nice!
Look at me go!
And now we're gonna go back here, and we're gonna do this.
Boom!
Yoink!
I should have done that closer to the wall, just in case there was a secret room.
Let's go.
I mean, I have pretty good damage now.
Wonderful.
More range, tier size, why not?
No special rooms, we move on.
Poop present.
That's a good omen.
I think I'll save my money.
Technology 2!
Minus tiers, replaces tiers from the left eye with a continuous unlimited range laser.
Yeah, dude!
But what is technology 1?
Oh shit, it doesn't go through stones, though.
That's too bad.
Hey, dude.
I need spectral tiers.
That would make this amazing.
You can't let the tomatoes grow.
Shit!
Aww!
I'm taking so much unnecessary damage right now.
What the heck is that?
Fragmented cart!
New floors will generate an additional secret room?
Oh hell yeah!
That's freaking awesome!
And you know what?
I think this item actually made that spawn just now.
The wishbone.
No, was that a room reward?
It may have been.
Oh yeah, the unlimited range is freakin' baller.
I really need to abuse that as much as possible.
No item?
No key.
Let's go over here.
I love technology.
Oh, let's kill this thing.
And that one...
I mean, it's not a lot of damage, but it's safe damage.
Most of the time.
Oh my god!
I'm fucking cornered!
Okay.
You can definitely tell that my normal tiers do way more damage.
Oi, oi!
Why was I curious about that?
I'm starting to play a little careless for no reason.
I gotta tighten that up a bit.
Discipline needs to come back.
Uh, no key still.
Wait!
Uh, where the hell is the boss?
Must be down here.
I think I wanna get in there.
Mom's ring?
Sponsor random rune, or what is a rune?
Soul Stone.
What is a Soul Stone?
Oh, that's a Soul Stone.
Uh, did we see any Xs?
I wasn't really paying attention.
Xs, Xs, Xs.
None in here.
But here's the thing, it says floor decoration, maybe spiderwebs count.
That's a decoration, isn't it?
Let's try it.
Nope, that's to the next level.
Shit.
Oh well, now we know.
Too bad.
Alright, this is gonna be so easy.
Dodge that.
Oh, I've never seen that before!
Spawn spiders?
That's a new trick.
Nice.
More tiers?
Is that actually gonna increase my laser as well?
Wait, how do I even get to the other one without picking it up?
Let's see, upon entering each room, a skull mar- oh, that's the- oh.
Yes!
And this?
Striking in- oh no, that one's fine.
Dude, we're gonna start killing people in order.
It's gonna be so much easier.
Last time I had this, I think I was on Eulith or something.
Where I couldn't easily aim.
Let's just double check here.
Uh, yeah, if all enemies are killed, I think it's awarded with a pickup or small permanence.
That boost!
Uh, let's do this one.
There's no- there's no mark on them!
Maybe it's only some rooms.
I-
I guess it doesn't apply to challenge rooms.
I can't believe I got hit again.
But maybe it's for the best, I gain more damage that way.
Yeah, it's- it's strategic.
No.
That requires two keys.
Wow.
Oh, this guy first!
Yeah!
Oh, this is great!
Alright, let me just play this safe.
What the- Wait, which one is it on?
Is it the first one?
It's gotta be.
Yeah!
Did I... get a stat reward?
What did I get?
I don't know what I got.
Multidimensional baby.
Conjoined, familiar, that follows Isaac's movements on a deli- Oh, right!
I had this in greed mode, I believe.
So that if I go like this...
Look how...
They're like advanced now.
So if I move back like this, that's how to do it.
Slowly move back.
Ooh.
Very sick.
Yeah, it is.
Thank you.
Also, what was this thing I had?
New floors will generate an additional secret room!
Okay, we really gotta start bombing the shit out of these walls soon.
Not yet, though.
Oh!
I thought I couldn't pick it up!
That's definitely a reward for killing it in the right order.
Which one now?
Wait, there's no marks?
What is this scam?
Okay, that one, that one.
We have this guy.
Why are there no marks?
Okay, there we go, there we go.
They have to pop up first before the marks are being applied.
That's weird.
Dude, that's amazing.
I love- I love this mark system!
Oh, let's not kill random enemies then.
This guy.
Then we have this guy.
I think I fucked it up.
Yeah, I messed it up.
This is so much fun, man.
Alright, alright, come on.
Wow, static grease!
Okay, he just died somehow.
Ah, more static grease!
Dude, this is great!
Oh, that was the guy.
Oh, that's gonna be tough, though.
Yeah!
Ah, rip, rip, rip, rip.
I think if I see something as difficult as that, I should just not even go for it.
Too risky.
Oh, God.
Absolutely not.
Okay, 24 monies, what's that?
Voodoo head?
Spawns an additional curse room on each new floor?
What is a curse room?
Improved layouts and rewards within curse rooms.
Also costs us one coin to spawn.
I mean, okay.
I don't know what curse rooms are, but...
I guess that's good.
We can go for this one to get some keys.
Actually, you know, donate.
Wow, no breakpoint at 250.
I gained luck!
I think there's just an inherent random chance to gain luck when you donate.
However small.
It's just there.
I don't think it's breakpoint related.
Oh, God.
Yeah, they died in the wrong order.
Oh!
Sweet.
Did I actually kill them in the right order?
I can't see what I just got.
Rainbow worm.
Cheers cycle through different worm effects.
Oh, it's a trinket.
Wait a second!
I just realized something.
Oh, no, nevermind.
Oh, that is so cool!
All right, I think I'll keep this.
That's definitely pretty cool.
It's weird, but I think it's cool.
It's gonna be nice.
Boss time!
Not this way.
Wait, why are my stats being...
Wait, is that the rainbow worm?
Oh, plus five damage.
Less shot speed.
Hold on.
Oh, my.
Okay, you know what?
No, no, no, no.
I don't like that.
I need to be consistent.
I can't.
I can't do that.
Nope.
It's too much.
We need consistency here.
In this house, we don't randomize.
The damage!
More damage!
I like it.
Very good.
And we can go in here.
Okay, what do we got?
Contract from below decreases likelihood of a room clip.
The Book of Sin spawns a random pickup.
Nope.
Nope, nope, nope, nope.
We stick to the hearts.
I'm not gonna make this mistake again.
Wow, two?
Wait.
Okay.
So that's a curse room, I guess.
Gotta be, right?
Hmm...
I'm not gonna go in yet, though, because I need more HP for that.
Oh, shit.
We gotta kill this guy first.
Bro!
Fuck!
I almost just sacrificed everything for that.
We cannot play this game.
We gotta just kill things.
Jesus.
B-b-b-b-b-b-b!
Oh.
We-we can't play it!
Gotta don't play like that.
That
isn't it?
More.
There's more?
Huh?
I have...
no idea what I died to!
Oh, I guess I died to a poop?
I don't know what that drawing is.
Looks like a tiny poop?
Honestly, in this game, I'm not surprised.
Dying to poop.
Well, that's it.
Frickin' nailed the supposedly hard part of the game, the challenges.
The normal mode, though, I just can't seem to win for some reason.
What's up with that, eh?
That's weird.
Cheers.
You just joined?
No, I'm sorry about that.
Bad timing.
The challenges were insanely fun.
I definitely gotta do, like, consistent amount of challenges every stream now.
How many heart kills today I just woke up?
Five.
As much as I love calling you blind, I would have also died to that.
What did I just die to?
Like, was it a little... it must have been a creature, I guess.
I had no idea where the hell that was.
No, it was a camel!
It was a camel, flushed!
Brother.
That's crazy.
Man, that was such a good run, too.
That's so sad.
I think if I hadn't died there and I had gotten just one more heart, I could have taken that all the way to the end.
That was a crazy run.
Have you tried the 30-second challenge?
No, I haven't.
I'm kind of going from top to bottom right now.
And I did three challenges today and I won them all.
First try on all of them.
I mean, A.
Kerr, I already failed one of the challenges, right?
I failed the Solar System one.
I tried that challenge, I don't even know when, maybe like three or four streams ago.
So I can't say I will one-shot every challenge.
But from now on I will.
Oh yeah, first one doesn't count!
True!
You're right, Frank.
Some people on YouTube are trying to nearly 100% unlock everything without dying once.
How are you able to do that?
That is some inhuman shit.
Holy Christ.
You should try April Fool's.
Oh yeah, there was a challenge called April Fool's, right?
That's what you mean?
I can't?
Why not?
Because I got to do it on the first of April or what?
I mean, I'm going to try all the challenges, of course.
Also, some of the challenges I haven't even unlocked yet.
Like there's a bunch of empty entries, you know, in the list.
You're truly the champion of playing wiki games blind?
I wouldn't even call... Why would you call this a wiki game?
There's nothing here that's...
I mean, okay, some things are a little obscure, I guess.
But, I mean, this is just a game.
This is no different than Hades to me.
I'm not clueless.
Guys, I'm a routine gamer.
I've been gaming all my life.
Like, I'm doing fine.
This is totally good.
What's my favorite item so far?
That's a good question.
Let me think.
What is my favorite item?
I'm thinking of the circle now.
The ludovico technique or whatever it was called.
Oh, you're specifically asking about active item?
Because then converter, yes.
But if you're asking like overall item...
Oh, wait, no, no, no.
It's got to be the laser.
The laser.
That or ludovico?
The red infinite laser?
Oh, man.
Yeah, I mean, it's just another excuse to become Azazel, right?
Anything that gets me closer to Azazel is a W.
Flight?
Yes.
Laser?
Black body?
Yes.
Oh, I'm talking about the brimstone.
The plan was to play Eulith today, actually.
But then I got absorbed by the challenges a little too hard.
Next time I'm going to play Eulith.
In fact, I think I'll do the same thing next time as well.
Where I keep asking you guys in the beginning what I should be doing today.
Like which characters you want to see, you know?
Because I think that's fun.
That way I can change it up a bit.
Because sometimes you get locked into a lane, right?
And you want to go only Azazel, for example.
So I think that's kind of fun.
If we do that every time.
You know, you can go, oh, you should do this challenge.
Or you should play this character.
Or something like that, you know?
What a people pleaser.
I know, I know.
I try to please the people.
Oh, yeah.
On my birthday, we're going to do a full Azazel day.
Because it'll be presents all around, man.
It's going to be win after win.
I guarantee you, the next time I jump on Azazel, it's going to be like the easiest win of all time.
It's just going to fall into my lap.
I'm telling you.
Whatever that is.
By the way, Azazel is not easy to play, okay?
You start with no red heart, so if you lose all your health, you're done.
Just saying, you know, you've got to play it smart, like me.
You've got to have some IQ points and some finger speed and some constitution.
That's not something everyone has, you know?
I'm just saying.
Exactly.
It's for the god gamers.
I'm a special, special talents.
Definitely the hardest character.
I'm just, you know, built different.
The game was a 100% wiki game before DLCs and quality of life updates.
We didn't have item description or extra odds.
Huh?
Okay, I see how you would use a wiki in that case.
Because how the fuck are you going to play the game otherwise?
Okay, that's crazy, though.
That's kind of akin to Minecraft before there were recipe books, right?
I would say that's probably the same level of absurdness.
That's crazy, man.
Item description ruined it?
What do you mean?
This game would suck without it, at least for me.
I'm talking about me.
I would not have any fun if there were no item descriptions.
I'm just going to sit there and guess all day?
No way, that's not fun.
It's like going into a room that's totally dark, you can't see anything.
And the guys in the back are just throwing random shit at you and you gotta guess.
You're like, ah fuck, what was that?
It was an apple.
Ah, what is that?
It's a wrench.
That's not fun.
I just want to know what I'm getting hit by, you know?
Why do you stream so little?
I don't think I do.
Nowadays I'm streaming every second day or so.
Two things, I want to keep it fresh for myself as well as you, right?
So, I can't play games seven hours a day and actually enjoy it the full seven hours.
I'm also recording videos for YouTube, of course, but...
Yeah, I guess I'm just not built for gaming for extended periods like that.
Only certain games I can do that with.
World of Warcraft being one of them and potentially Starcraft 2.
Yeah.
That's like the... it's actually kind of a weird thing about going full time with the streaming.
Because I thought, oh, I'm gonna fucking play all day every day, you know?
And I could do that.
I could put out like seven hours of content every day, technically, if I wanted to.
But that's just not... that's gonna be too much content.
Like, there's no way you guys can even keep up with that.
And it's also not as fun for me.
So it's weird, I'm actually kind of working a little less now or playing games less than I thought I would.
Because I'm just not getting enjoyment out of any amount of hours after three or four, you know?
I am a full time content creator now.
Alexis, I have not played Warcraft 3 that much.
I've played like a tiny amount of the campaign.
I pretty much don't even remember anything from the campaign.
So I definitely want to play it.
I even played Warcraft 1.
Like a year ago, I put it all on YouTube too.
Like the whole game in one video.
And the plan was to play Warcraft 2 and then 3 afterwards, but I just never got around to doing it.
Do you miss your astrophysicist job?
A little bit?
Mostly no.
Simply because the whole research thing just wasn't for me, honestly.
Like when I started my PhD, I realized that I liked coding way more than I liked doing, you know, writing papers, reading papers and stuff like that.
It just wasn't fun for me.
I definitely discovered that coding is so much fun.
And then I happened to start the whole, well, accidentally almost do the YouTube thing, right?
And then I was like, you know what?
I'm gonna stop this and try the YouTube thing.
So I just jumped in full.
And it paid off, I guess.
I saw the content creation about two years ago.
Thereabouts.
How are you feeling about Isaac now that he's passed the honeymoon phase?
Oh, man.
I wouldn't even say this game has a honeymoon phase.
I think I'm liking it more than I did when I started.
Like, I like this game even more now than I did the very first and second day.
Way more.
The reason is...
Oh, let me actually back up a bit.
The first time I played this, which was on the first stream, I think I even beat the game on the first stream.
I got the credits.
I was honestly like, what?
That's it?
And I was kind of afraid that, oh, I'm gonna go through this like five levels every time.
Like, that doesn't sound fun at all.
What the fuck is this?
You know?
But the more I've played the game and the more it's opening up and suddenly I'm fucking digging deeper, finding more items and all these challenges in the green mode, like, all of this is adding up, you know?
And I'm actually liking it more.
Like, way more than I did in the beginning.
So I would say the honeymoon phase is slowly starting.
Right now.
Like, this is the honeymoon phase now.
Isn't that weird?
I know I'm not the most attentive gamer, Svarios.
I try my best.
I mean, the thing is, a lot of people miss stuff, they just don't know it.
Because they don't have people, you know, looking over their shoulder.
It's gonna happen.
Over time I'm gonna, you know, notice things a lot more, of course.
I'm probably not gonna play Terraria again, Ravel.
Unless they fix the 200 issues I have with the game.
Which I doubt they will, because it's like, that's what makes Terraria Terraria.
Yeah, I am actually gonna take notes about this game at some point.
But I haven't felt the need yet.
There's nothing yet that made me think, oh, I gotta write this down.
Maybe a couple times, actually.
With the machine that gives me, uh...
Ah, what is it called?
Premonitions?
You know, you get a text saying, you suck.
Or, you should quit.
Like, sometimes it'll say weird stuff like, follow the white rabbit or whatever.
Yeah, fortune tell with that one.
I feel like some of that was a little bit cryptic, so I wanted to write it down.
And maybe I will.
Not him, I don't know.
It's not gonna be anytime soon.
But it's gonna happen at some point.
I mean, you can also just watch me play Isaac when I play Judas.
That's gonna be a rage dream.
That's the perfect recipe for rage.
Alright, guys.
That was a fantastic round of challenges and...
Well, I would say I also did pretty well.
In fact, the Isaac run I did, in the very beginning, was pretty respectable.
I got pretty far with that.
I'm gonna end it here.
Thanks for watching.
It is amazing to have you guys here watching this, enjoying it and subscribing.
I see all of you in the activity feed, by the way.
I really appreciate it.
Thank you so much.
It means the world to me.
Like I said, one of the other streams, you're actually funding my crack addiction.
But it's a good thing.
It's a good thing.
It's not a bad thing.
I love this crack.
This crack is good.
I'll see you around.